Call them slobs. Call them jerks. Call them gross. Just
don't call them when you're in trouble.
Police Academy is a comedy, crime film directed by Hugh Wilson.
New rules enforced by the Lady Mayoress mean that sex, weight, height and
intelligence need no longer be a factor for joining the Police Force.
This opens the floodgates for all and sundry to enter the Police
Academy, much to the chagrin of the instructors.
Not everyone is there through choice, though.
Social misfit Mahoney has been forced to sign up as the only alternative to a jail sentence
and it doesn't take long before he falls foul of the boorish Lieutenant Harris.
But before long, Mahoney realises that he is enjoying being a
police cadet and decides he wants to stay...
while Harris decides he wants Mahoney out!
Carey Mahoney, played by Steve Guttenberg.
Karen Thompson, played by Kim Cattrall.
Lieutenant Harris, played by G.W. Bailey.
Moses Hightower, played by Bubba Smith.
Leslie Barbara, played by Donovan Scott.
Commandant Lassard, played by George Gaynes.
Police Academy is a 1984 American comedy film directed by Hugh Wilson in
his directorial debut, and distributed by Warner Bros.
Its storyline follows a new recruitment policy for an unnamed city's police academy to take
in any recruit who wishes to apply and study to become a police officer.
The film stars Steve Guttenberg, Kim Cattrall and G.
The film was produced by The Ladd Company.
It premiered on March 23, 1984.
It grossed $8.5 million in its opening weekend and more than $149 million worldwide, against a
budget of $4.8 million, and remains the most successful film of the series as of 2022.
The film spawned six sequels in the Police Academy franchise, and is the
only film in the franchise to be rated R by the MPAA.
The film explores themes of trainer, recruit, shenanigan, police academy.
The tone is lighthearted.